About Me

Experienced, personable hands-on technologist focused on rapid, pragmatic, iterative delivery. Multi-certified Azure expert.

Cloud Architecture, Software Development, Applied AI and Analytics, Data Engineering, DevOps/Automation and Cybersecurity.

Skilled technical seller, consultant, presenter. I listen, learn, create clarity, and help to deliver success.

Objective

Technical lead/delivery role in product/platform engineering and program management, technical sales, consulting.

Domains: cloud, architecture, data/applied AI, development/DevOps, integration/automation.

Experience

Cloud Architect, DevOps Engineer, Data Engineer

SES Satellites | 5/2022-current (consultant)

Led Azure architecture, DevOps engineering, infrastructure automation, .NET/Python development, integration, data engineering and cybersecurity compliance for cloudnative greenfield revenue optimization and yield management platforms.

Azure Cybersecurity Engineer



Microsoft | 10/2022-7/2023 (consultant)

Azure architecture and workload remediation for Azure Tenant Baseline NIST cybersecurity control implementations across organizational divisions. Built artifacts and documentation, trained technical teams, executed technical work.

Lead Azure Architect

<epam> EPAM Systems | 1/2022-4/2022

Led Azure architecture and migration process design on financial-industry datacenterto-Azure migration projects.

Global Cloud Solution Architect | Customer Success



Microsoft | 11/2015-12/2021

Technical lead for enterprise Azure client mission-critical projects. Led solution architecture, technical delivery and represented clients to product engineering groups. Led solution development, technical training, hackathons, and executive briefings.

Cloud Solution Architect in Global, National, Regional and Financial Services Industry roles. Member of Azure Mission-Critical team that created reference architectures and deploy-ready deliverables published to Microsoft Learn. Selected for Senior Technical Leadership Program and Quest Engineering Rotation.

Notable successes included retail store floor map flow and dwell analysis using store video and Microsoft AI Cognitive Services, which led to significant client Azure commitment; high-volume financial document analytics using Microsoft AI Cognitive Services; infosec-driven compute refresh automation in highly complex financial industry context; multiple competitive cloud wins; more.

Program Manager with Azure Cosmos DB engineering group. Delivered deploy-ready sample applications and contributed to product documentation and code libraries.

Contact



Manchester, NH / Boston, MA



p@elazem.com



+1-603-275-6901



in LinkedIn: pelazem



GitHub: plzm



Blog: plzm.blog

Certifications: credly/pelazem

Skills

- Cloud Architecture + Design
- Development, DevOps, Scripting
- Applied AI + Analytics
- Data Modeling and Engineering
- Infrastructure, Automation, Integration
- Technical Sales, Consulting, Presenting
- Team Leadership + Training
- Program + Project Management
- Azure, Al Cognitive Services, Synapse, Cosmos DB, Azure SQL, App Services/Functions, Azure Kubernetes, Azure DevOps, .NET/C#, Git, GitHub, GitHub Actions, Python, SQL, Powershell, Bash, CLI, many more

Education

B.Sc., Engineering & Applied Science

California Institute of Technology, 1994



International Baccalaureate (IB)

Bonn American HS, Germany, 1988

International

Native German. Fluent French. International residency experience.

Director of Technology, Lead Developer

4D Technologies CADLearning | 6/2012-11/2015

Led zero-downtime migration of customer platforms to AWS. Modernized digital content creation platforms and processes, analytics, reporting, and built partner integration APIs.

Built DevOps team and technology roadmap. Created operations and support capabilities resulting in ongoing customer satisfaction ratings > 99% and systems uptime > 99.9%.

Principal Consultant

Net Gain Solutions | 2006-2014

Technical project engagements including client/API .NET/C# development, DevOps, data engineering and design, BI and analytics, off-the-shelf system implementations.

Clients included Fidelity Investments, Horizon Beverage Company, C&J Bus Lines, Borealis Ventures, Nexamp, American Health Centers, Liberty International, Global Relief Technologies / US Department of Defense, Override, Middle East Bakery.

Director of Operations

Message Secure Corporation | 2005

Created IT Operations and Compliance teams at financial-industry technology provider. Led successful response to federal (FDIC, FFIEC) examinations. Initiated COBIT IT control framework implementation for SAS 70 certification process.

Lead Developer, Director of Technology

<u>Trade Wings | 2000-2005</u>

Built web-based supply chain and procurement platform. Co-created supply chain optimization algorithms which yielded double-digit % cost savings for manufacturing customers. Team member for successful ISO 9001:2000 certification.

Senior Developer, Development Manager

Furniture.com | 1998-2000

Built leading B2C e-commerce site. Staffed and led web development team.

Developer

Deloitte & Touche / DRT Systems | 1998

Member of development team that built Liberty Mutual Insurance's first Java and web insurance claims processing platform.

Consultant Developer

David Bowie | 1998

Built pop star's first B2C web site, bowieart.com, whose success validated later Bowie online investments. Implemented online purchasing and payment processing.

Systems Administrator

Neurotec / Artificial Life | 1996-1998

Managed organization and client infrastructure, operations, and web sites.

Environmental Engineer

TRC Environmental | 1995-1996

Performed Clean Air Act plant audits, permitting, plume impact analysis, and compliance for clients including General Motors. Built first company web site.